First love burns brightest.
Bright Star is a drama, romance film directed by Jane Campion.
In 1818, high-spirited young Fanny Brawne finds herself increasingly intrigued by the handsome
but aloof poet John Keats, who lives next door to her family friends the Dilkes.
After reading a book of his poetry, she finds herself
even more drawn to the taciturn Keats.
Although he agrees to teach her about poetry, Keats cannot act on his reciprocated feelings
for Fanny, since as a struggling poet he has no money to support a wife.
Fanny Brawne, played by Abbie Cornish.
John Keats, played by Ben Whishaw.
Mr. Brown, played by Paul Schneider.
Mrs. Brawne, played by Kerry Fox.
Toots, played by Edie Martin.
Samuel, played by Thomas Brodie-Sangster.
Bright Star is a 2009 biographical romantic drama film,
written and directed by Jane Campion.
It is based on the last three years of the life of poet John Keats (played by Ben
Whishaw) and his romantic relationship with Fanny Brawne (Abbie Cornish).
Campion's screenplay was inspired by a 1997 biography of Keats by
Andrew Motion, who served as a script consultant.
Bright Star was in the main competition at the 2009 Cannes Film
Festival, and was first shown to the public on 15 May 2009.
The film's title is a reference to a sonnet by Keats titled "Bright star, would I
were stedfast as thou art", which he wrote while he was with Brawne.
The film explores themes of london, england, poet,
duringcreditsstinger, woman director, 19th century.
The tone is emotional.